Tufts Observer UP055
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Tufts Observer
1969 -- 2021
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Office for Campus Life
UP055
9.7 Linear Feet
23 Volumes
397 Digital Object(s)
1 Web sites
Arrangement
This collection is organized into series by box with and additional series for web crawls.
Biographical / Historical
The Observer replaced the Tufts Weekly as the weekly student-published newspaper in 1969. In 1973 "Tufts" was added to the name. It is the official newspaper of record for Tufts University. The Observer receives funding from the student activities budget.
In December 2001, the Observer changed format from a full-size newspaper to a newsmagazine. It continues to be published each Friday during the academic year.
Related Materials
UP056, Tufts Weekly, DCA
Scope and Contents
This collection contains issues of the Tufts Observer and web crawls documenting its web presence. It covers university news, sports, and events, primarily on the Medford campus. It also includes editorials, announcements and calendar items of events, and nationally syndicated comics. Volume numbering begins with vol. 1 in 1969, and varies in frequency. Sometimes a volume covers one semester, and other times one academic year.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
- Tufts Observer, 2015; UP055-001 (Box 1)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
- Observer, 1969 -- 1970; UP055.001; 1 Volumes; 36 Digital Object(s)
  Scope and Contents
  This series consists of bound volumes of the Tufts Observer newspaper, dated from January 29, 1969 to May 1, 1970. In 1969, the Observer replaced the Tufts Weekly as the weekly student-published paper. The Observer states that its objective is to be 'the newspaper of record' for Tufts University. The Observer covers current events and university news and sports. Typical features include editorials and opinion pieces, a calendar of events, art and culture articles, creative works, and comics.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged chronologically.
  - Observer, 1969-01-29; UP055.001.001.00001; 1 Digital Object(s); 16 Megabytes (Box 1)
  - Observer, 1969-02-04; UP055.001.001.00002; 1 Digital Object(s); 10 Megabytes (Box 1)
  - Observer, 1969-02-07; UP055.001.001.00003; 1 Digital Object(s); 10 Megabytes (Box 1)
  - Observer, 1969-02-14; UP055.001.001.00004; 1 Digital Object(s); 15 Megabytes (Box 1)
  - Observer, 1969-02-18; UP055.001.001.00005; 1 Digital Object(s); 10 Megabytes (Box 1)
  - Observer, 1969-02-21; UP055.001.001.00006; 1 Digital Object(s); 8 Megabytes (Box 1)
  - Observer, 1969-02-25; UP055.001.001.00007; 1 Digital Object(s); 9 Megabytes (Box 1)
  - Observer, 1969-02-28; UP055.001.001.00008; 1 Digital Object(s); 8 Megabytes (Box 1)
  - Observer, 1969-03-07; UP055.001.001.00009; 1 Digital Object(s); 26 Megabytes (Box 1)
    [Afro-American Cultural Center] Recommendation that such a center be established at Tufts, p. 1; [Afro-American Society] Open letter to President Hallowell, p. 18.
  - Observer, 1969-03-14; UP055.001.001.00010; 1 Digital Object(s); 27 Megabytes (Box 1)
  - Observer, 1969-03-28; UP055.001.001.00011; 1 Digital Object(s); 25 Megabytes (Box 1)
  - Observer, 1969-04-04; UP055.001.001.00012; 1 Digital Object(s); 16 Megabytes (Box 1)
  - Observer, 1969-04-11; UP055.001.001.00013; 1 Digital Object(s); 22 Megabytes (Box 1)
    ACLU (American Civil Liberties Union) Urges students to abandon violence. p 10; Academic Calendar 1969-70.
  - Observer, 1969-04-16; UP055.001.001.00014; 1 Digital Object(s); 6 Megabytes (Box 1)
  - Observer, 1969-04-18; UP055.001.001.00015; 1 Digital Object(s); 17 Megabytes (Box 1)
  - Observer, 1969-04-25; UP055.001.001.00016; 1 Digital Object(s); 19 Megabytes (Box 1)
    [All Around Club] Election of Officers.
  - Observer, 1969-09-08; UP055.001.001.00017; 1 Digital Object(s); 20 Megabytes (Box 1)
  - Observer, 1969-09-12; UP055.001.001.00018; 1 Digital Object(s); 9 Megabytes (Box 1)
  - Observer, 1969-09-19; UP055.001.001.00019; 1 Digital Object(s); 16 Megabytes (Box 1)
    Admissions. p. 8. [Alpha Epsilon Pi] Considers major changes.
  - Observer, 1969-09-26; UP055.001.001.00020; 1 Digital Object(s); 21 Megabytes (Box 1)
    [Alumni in residence] Established resource division
  - Observer, 1969-10-03; UP055.001.001.00021; 1 Digital Object(s); 25 Megabytes (Box 1)
    [Afro-American Society] Urges Tufts to challenge discrimination, p. 1; Commentary from, p. 8. [Alpha Epsilon Pi] Plans advance.
  - Observer, 1969-10-10; UP055.001.001.00022; 1 Digital Object(s); 19 Megabytes (Box 1)
    [Afro-American Society] Urges Tufts to challenge discrimination, p. 1; Commentary from, p. 6.
  - Observer, 1969-10-17; UP055.001.001.00023; 1 Digital Object(s); 27 Megabytes (Box 1)
    [Afro-American Society] Rally, p. 1.
  - Observer, 1969-10-24; UP055.001.001.00024; 1 Digital Object(s); 24 Megabytes (Box 1)
  - Observer, 1969-10-31; UP055.001.001.00025; 1 Digital Object(s); 20 Megabytes (Box 1)
  - Observer, 1969-11-06; UP055.001.001.00026; 1 Digital Object(s); 6 Megabytes (Box 1)
  - Observer, 1969-11-07; UP055.001.001.00027; 1 Digital Object(s); 18 Megabytes (Box 1)
    Academic Calendar 1969. Evelyn Stern. Quarter System at Tufts?; [Afro-American Society] Criticism of adminstration, p. 1, 12.
    - Volpe Construction Protest, 1969-11-07; UP055.001.001.00027.00001 (Box 1)
      Policemen and workers at the Lewis Hall construction site; Volpe Construction Company protest
      --Activism; Black people; Policemen; Dormitories; Tufts University; Volpe Construction Company
  - Observer, 1969-11-12; UP055.001.001.00028; 1 Digital Object(s); 6 Megabytes (Box 1)
  - Observer, 1969-11-14; UP055.001.001.00029; 1 Digital Object(s); 16 Megabytes (Box 1)
  - Observer, 1969-11-21; UP055.001.001.00030; 1 Digital Object(s); 24 Megabytes (Box 1)
  - Observer, 1969-12-05; UP055.001.001.00031; 1 Digital Object(s); 30 Megabytes (Box 1)
    Academic Calendar 1969. Evelyn Stern. Quarter System at Tufts?; Academic Calendar 1969-70. Quarter system received inconclusively at forum. Academic Calendar 1970-71. John W. Schlessinger (Faculty). A new/old calendar.; Administration 1969. (Primack, Philip N.) Criticism of ("Because").; Administration 1969. Counseling at Tufts.
  - Observer, 1970-02-02; UP055.001.001.00032; 1 Digital Object(s); 21 Megabytes (Box 1)
    Academic Ceremonies 1970. Degrees. New Bachelor of Science degree created in Civil Engineering; [Afro-American Society] Court overrules Afro's injunction pleas, p. 7; [Afro-American Society] November's Children (equal employment opportunities in the construction business), p. 4.
  - Observer, 1970-02-06; UP055.001.001.00033; 1 Digital Object(s); 16 Megabytes (Box 1)
  - Observer, 1970-02-13; UP055.001.001.00034; 1 Digital Object(s); 23 Megabytes (Box 1)
    Academic Calendar 1970-71. Editorial.
  - Observer, 1970-02-20; UP055.001.001.00035; 1 Digital Object(s); 22 Megabytes (Box 1)
    Academic Calendar 1970-71. Suggestions for.
  - Observer, 1970-02-27; UP055.001.001.00036; 1 Digital Object(s); 23 Megabytes (Box 1)
  - Observer, 1970-03-06; UP055.001.001.00037; 1 Digital Object(s); 28 Megabytes (Box 1)
    [Afro-American Society] New officers, p. 4.
  - Observer, 1970-03-13; UP055.001.001.00038; 1 Digital Object(s); 22 Megabytes (Box 1)
  - Observer, 1970-03-27; UP055.001.001.00039; 1 Digital Object(s); 22 Megabytes (Box 1)
  - Observer, 1970-04-03; UP055.001.001.00040; 1 Digital Object(s); 16 Megabytes (Box 1)
  - Observer Supplement, 1970-04-03; UP055.001165; 1 Digital Object(s); 5 Megabytes (Box 1)
  - Observer, 1970-04-10; UP055.001.001.00041; 1 Digital Object(s); 22 Megabytes (Box 1)
  - Observer, 1970-04-17; UP055.001.001.00042; 1 Digital Object(s); 22 Megabytes (Box 1)
  - Observer, 1970-04-24; UP055.001.001.00043; 1 Digital Object(s); 22 Megabytes (Box 1)
    Edward H Lareau [A1961] Alumni council voting; [African-American Center] Sponsors Black art festival, p. 3; Edward H. Lareau [A1961] Alumni council voting
  - Observer, 1970-05-01; UP055.001.001.00044; 1 Digital Object(s); 28 Megabytes (Box 1)
- Observer, 1970 -- 1971; UP055.002; 1 Volumes; 47 Digital Object(s)
  This series consists of bound volumes of the Tufts Observer newspaper, dated from September 18, 1970 to May 5, 1971. In 1969, the Observer replaced the Tufts Weekly as the weekly student-published paper. The Observer states that its objective is to be 'the newspaper of record' for Tufts University. The Observer covers current events and university news and sports. Typical features include editorials and opinion pieces, a calendar of events, art and culture articles, creative works, and comics.
  - Observer, 1970-09-18; UP055.002.002.00001; 1 Digital Object(s); 17 Megabytes (Box 2)
    Administration 1970. Tufts Refuses Government Request. Administration 1970-71. Tufts administration revamped (includes photo).
  - Observer, 1970-09-25; UP055.002.002.00002; 1 Digital Object(s); 18 Megabytes (Box 2)
    [Administration 1970-71] Day Care Center.
  - Observer, 1970-10-02; UP055.002.002.00003; 1 Digital Object(s); 21 Megabytes (Box 2)
    [Administration 1970-71] Day Care Center. Administration 1970. Changes in. [Alinsky, Saul] Lectures at Tufts (incl. photo).
  - Observer, 1970-10-09; UP055.002.002.00004; 1 Digital Object(s); 21 Megabytes (Box 2)
    [Charles Abbe] Tenure and "common good" Tenure and "Tufts good" p. 6, 12. Administration 1970. Tenure.
  - Observer, 1970-10-16; UP055.002.002.00005; 1 Digital Object(s); 20 Megabytes (Box 2)
  - Observer, 1970-10-23; UP055.002.002.00006; 1 Digital Object(s); 21 Megabytes (Box 2)
    [Administration 1970-71] Day Care Center. Administration 1970-71. Disadvantaged given jobs by Tufts. Freeland K. Abbott; Outstanding Educators of America, p. 5.
  - Observer, 1970-10-30; UP055.002.002.00007; 1 Digital Object(s); 16 Megabytes (Box 2)
    Administration 1970-71. Tufts hiring practices. [Administration 1970-71] Day Care Center.
  - Observer, 1970-11-06; UP055.002.002.00008; 1 Digital Object(s); 24 Megabytes (Box 2)
  - Observer, 1970-11-13; UP055.002.002.00009; 1 Digital Object(s); 18 Megabytes (Box 2)
  - Observer, 1970-11-20; UP055.002.002.00010; 1 Digital Object(s); 27 Megabytes (Box 2)
  - Observer, 1970-12-01; UP055.002.002.00011; 1 Digital Object(s); 6 Megabytes (Box 2)
  - Observer, 1970-12-04; UP055.002.002.00012; 1 Digital Object(s); 17 Megabytes (Box 2)
    Administration 1970-71. Day Care Center. Administration 1970-71. Tufts hiring practices.
  - Observer, 1970-12-11; UP055.002.002.00013; 1 Digital Object(s); 21 Megabytes (Box 2)
    Administration 1970-71. Day Care Center.
  - Observer, 1971-01-25; UP055.002.002.00014; 1 Digital Object(s); 5 Megabytes (Box 2)
    Administration 1970-71. To open in February; [Afro-American Society] Submits proposal for Black Student institute, p. 1.
  - Observer, 1971-02-16; UP055.002.002.00015; 1 Digital Object(s); 10 Megabytes (Box 2)
    Robert Albert (Adm) Newly appointed head of Equal Oppurtunity and Inter-group Relations office (incl. photo).
  - Observer, 1971-02-18; UP055.002.002.00016; 1 Digital Object(s); 5 Megabytes (Box 2)
  - Observer, 1971-02-19; UP055.002.002.00017; 1 Digital Object(s); 11 Megabytes (Box 2)
    [Afro-American Society] Submits proposal for Black Student Institute, p. 3.
  - Observer, 1971-02-22; UP055.002.002.00018; 1 Digital Object(s); 5 Megabytes (Box 2)
    Administration 1970-71. Tufts hiring practices.
  - Observer, 1971-02-23; UP055.002.002.00019; 1 Digital Object(s); 5 Megabytes (Box 2)
  - Observer, 1971-02-25; UP055.002.002.00020; 1 Digital Object(s); 5 Megabytes (Box 2)
    Freeland K. Abbott (Faculty); Death of, February 24, 1971, on board a ship en route to Pusan, Korea; p. 1,2.; [Advisory Subcommittee on Budget and University Priorities] New committee formed. p. 1.
  - Observer, 1971-02-26; UP055.001175; 1 Digital Object(s); 5 Megabytes (Box 2)
  - Observer, 1971-03-01; UP055.001176; 1 Digital Object(s); 5 Megabytes (Box 2)
  - Observer, 1971-03-02; UP055.002.002.00021; 1 Digital Object(s); 6 Megabytes (Box 2)
    Administration 1970-71. Begins operations. (includes photo).
  - Observer, 1971-03-04; UP055.002.002.00022; 1 Digital Object(s); 5 Megabytes (Box 2)
  - Observer, 1971-03-05; UP055.002.002.00023; 1 Digital Object(s); 5 Megabytes (Box 2)
  - Observer, 1971-03-08; UP055.002.002.00024; 1 Digital Object(s); 5 Megabytes (Box 2)
  - Observer, 1971-03-09; UP055.002.002.00025; 1 Digital Object(s); 5 Megabytes (Box 2)
    Administration 1971. Tufts University: no voluntary draft information.
  - Observer, 1971-03-11; UP055.002.002.00026; 1 Digital Object(s); 5 Megabytes (Box 2)
  - Observer, 1971-03-12; UP055.001177; 1 Digital Object(s); 4 Megabytes (Box 2)
  - Observer, 1971-03-15; UP055.002.002.00027; 1 Digital Object(s); 5 Megabytes (Box 2)
  - Observer, 1971-03-16; UP055.001178; 1 Digital Object(s); 5 Megabytes (Box 2)
  - Observer, 1971-03-18; UP055.002.002.00028; 1 Digital Object(s); 5 Megabytes (Box 2)
  - Observer, 1971-03-19; UP055.001179; 1 Digital Object(s); 5 Megabytes (Box 2)
  - Observer, 1971-03-22; UP055.002.002.00029; 1 Digital Object(s); 10 Megabytes (Box 2)
  - Observer, 1971-03-23; UP055.002.002.00030; 1 Digital Object(s); 5 Megabytes (Box 2)
  - Observer, 1971-03-25; UP055.002.002.00031; 1 Digital Object(s); 5 Megabytes (Box 2)
  - Observer, 1971-04-06; UP055.002.002.00032; 1 Digital Object(s); 5 Megabytes (Box 2)
  - Observer, 1971-04-08; UP055.002.002.00033; 1 Digital Object(s); 5 Megabytes (Box 2)
  - Observer, 1971-04-09; UP055.002.002.00034; 1 Digital Object(s); 5 Megabytes (Box 2)
  - Observer, 1971-04-12; UP055.002.002.00035; 1 Digital Object(s); 5 Megabytes (Box 2)
    Administration 1971. Rejects student reresentatives on tenure committee.
  - Observer, 1971-04-13; UP055.002.002.00036; 1 Digital Object(s); 5 Megabytes (Box 2)
  - Observer, 1971-04-15; UP055.002.002.00037; 1 Digital Object(s); 5 Megabytes (Box 2)
  - Observer, 1971-04-16; UP055.002.002.00038; 1 Digital Object(s); 5 Megabytes (Box 2)
  - Observer, 1971-04-20; UP055.002.002.00039; 1 Digital Object(s); 10 Megabytes (Box 2)
  - Observer, 1971-04-22; UP055.002.002.00040; 1 Digital Object(s); 5 Megabytes (Box 2)
  - Observer, 1971-04-23; UP055.002.002.00041; 1 Digital Object(s); 5 Megabytes (Box 2)
  - Observer, 1971-05-05; UP055.002.002.00042; 1 Digital Object(s); 11 Megabytes (Box 2)
    [Afro-American Society] Summer Institute, p. 4.
- Observer, 1971 -- 1972; UP055.003; 1 Volumes; 24 Digital Object(s)
  This series consists of bound volumes of the Tufts Observer newspaper, dated from September 24, 1971 to May 12, 1972. In 1969, the Observer replaced the Tufts Weekly as the weekly student-published paper. The Observer states that its objective is to be 'the newspaper of record' for Tufts University. The Observer covers current events and university news and sports. Typical features include editorials and opinion pieces, a calendar of events, art and culture articles, creative works, and comics.
  - Observer, 1971-09-24; UP055.003.003.00001; 1 Digital Object(s); 5 Megabytes (Box 3)
  - Observer, 1971-10-01; UP055.003.003.00002; 1 Digital Object(s); 21 Megabytes (Box 3)
  - Observer, 1971-10-08; UP055.003.003.00003; 1 Digital Object(s); 11 Megabytes (Box 3)
  - Observer, 1971-10-15; UP055.003.003.00004; 1 Digital Object(s); 22 Megabytes (Box 3)
  - Observer, 1971-10-22; UP055.003.003.00005; 1 Digital Object(s); 11 Megabytes (Box 3)
  - Observer, 1971-10-29; UP055.003.003.00006; 1 Digital Object(s); 16 Megabytes (Box 3)
  - Observer, 1971-11-05; UP055.003.003.00007; 1 Digital Object(s); 16 Megabytes (Box 3)
  - Observer, 1971-11-12; UP055.003.003.00008; 1 Digital Object(s); 10 Megabytes (Box 3)
  - Observer, 1971-11-19; UP055.003.003.00009; 1 Digital Object(s); 30 Megabytes (Box 3)
  - Observer, 1971-12-03; UP055.003.003.00010; 1 Digital Object(s); 14 Megabytes (Box 3)
  - Observer, 1972-02-15; UP055.003.003.00011; 1 Digital Object(s); 11 Megabytes (Box 3)
  - Observer, 1972-02-25; UP055.003.003.00012; 1 Digital Object(s); 22 Megabytes (Box 3)
  - Observer, 1972-03-03; UP055.003.003.00013; 1 Digital Object(s); 21 Megabytes (Box 3)
  - Observer, 1972-03-10; UP055.003.003.00014; 1 Digital Object(s); 15 Megabytes (Box 3)
  - Observer, 1972-03-17; UP055.003.003.00015; 1 Digital Object(s); 22 Megabytes (Box 3)
  - Observer, 1972-03-24; UP055.003.003.00016; 1 Digital Object(s); 21 Megabytes (Box 3)
  - Observer, 1972-03-30; UP055.003.003.00017; 1 Digital Object(s); 5 Megabytes (Box 3)
  - Observer, 1972-04-14; UP055.003.003.00018; 1 Digital Object(s); 16 Megabytes (Box 3)
  - Observer, 1972-04-21; UP055.003.003.00019; 1 Digital Object(s); 21 Megabytes (Box 3)
  - Observer, 1972-04-25; UP055.003.003.00020; 1 Digital Object(s); 5 Megabytes (Box 3)
  - Observer, 1972-04-28; UP055.003.003.00021; 1 Digital Object(s); 22 Megabytes (Box 3)
  - Observer, 1972-05-04; UP055.003.003.00022; 1 Digital Object(s); 10 Megabytes (Box 3)
  - Observer, 1972-05-12; UP055.003.003.00023; 1 Digital Object(s); 27 Megabytes (Box 3)
  - Observer Supplement, UP055.001166; 1 Digital Object(s); 5 Megabytes (Box 3)
- Observer, 1972 -- 1973; UP055.004; 1 Volumes; 28 Digital Object(s)
  This series consists of bound volumes of the Tufts Observer newspaper, dated from September 15, 1972 to May 11, 1973. In 1969, the Observer replaced the Tufts Weekly as the weekly student-published paper. Observer states that its objective is to be 'the newspaper of record' for Tufts University. The Observer covers current events and university news and sports. Typical features include editorials and opinion pieces, a calendar of events, art and culture articles, creative works, and comics.
  - Observer, 1972-09-15; UP055.004.004.00001; 1 Digital Object(s); 11 Megabytes (Box 4)
    Bella Abzug. Speaker at Tufts Lecture Series Attacks Nixon. Administration.1972-73. Shuttle Bus. New week-day shuttle ties New England Medical Center to campus, on trial b
  - Observer, 1972-09-22; UP055.004.004.00002; 1 Digital Object(s); 10 Megabytes (Box 4)
    Administration. Calendar Office Reopens, 1972. New head plans to develop new campus activities.
  - Observer, 1972-09-29; UP055.004.004.00003; 1 Digital Object(s); 17 Megabytes (Box 4)
    Administration.1972-73. Dean Steindler bans use, or sale of College Sampler, because of discount slips for Term Paper purchase; [Afro-American Society] Financially-pressed TCU, obliged to cut budget, p. 10.
  - Observer, 1972-10-06; UP055.004.004.00004; 1 Digital Object(s); 24 Megabytes (Box 4)
  - Observer, 1972-10-13; UP055.004.004.00005; 1 Digital Object(s); 22 Megabytes (Box 4)
  - Observer, 1972-10-20; UP055.004.004.00006; 1 Digital Object(s); 21 Megabytes (Box 4)
  - Observer, 1972-10-27; UP055.004.004.00007; 1 Digital Object(s); 23 Megabytes (Box 4)
  - Observer, 1972-11-03; UP055.004.004.00008; 1 Digital Object(s); 22 Megabytes (Box 4)
  - Observer Supplement, 1972-11-03; UP055.001167; 1 Digital Object(s); 18 Megabytes (Box 4)
  - Observer, 1972-11-10; UP055.004.004.00009; 1 Digital Object(s); 22 Megabytes (Box 4)
  - Observer, 1972-11-17; UP055.004.004.00010; 1 Digital Object(s); 22 Megabytes (Box 4)
    Academic Honors; Special open meeting to discuss Academic Honors at Tufts; P.15.
  - Observer, 1972-12-01; UP055.004.004.00011; 1 Digital Object(s); 29 Megabytes (Box 4)
    Robert Albert resigns as Director of Office of Equal Opportunity.
  - Observer, 1972-12-08; UP055.004.004.00012; 1 Digital Object(s); 24 Megabytes (Box 4)
    Administration. Richard Ferguson, 1972-73. Appointed Assistant to the President (includes photo).; [Admissions] Cr
  - Observer, 1973-01-11; UP055.004.004.00013; 1 Digital Object(s); 10 Megabytes (Box 4)
  - Observer, 1973-01-26; UP055.004.004.00014; 1 Digital Object(s); 16 Megabytes (Box 4)
  - Observer, 1973-02-05; UP055.004.004.00015; 1 Digital Object(s); 20 Megabytes (Box 4)
    [Admissions] No policy changes planned. p. 10.
  - Observer, 1973-02-16; UP055.004.004.00016; 1 Digital Object(s); 25 Megabytes (Box 4)
  - Observer, 1973-02-23; UP055.004.004.00017; 1 Digital Object(s); 20 Megabytes (Box 4)
    Administration. Povost of, 1972-73. Bresler concerned by Nixon's scholarship cuts.
  - Observer, 1973-03-02; UP055.004.004.00018; 1 Digital Object(s); 18 Megabytes (Box 4)
  - Observer, 1973-03-09; UP055.004.004.00019; 1 Digital Object(s); 19 Megabytes (Box 4)
  - Observer, 1973-03-16; UP055.004.004.00020; 1 Digital Object(s); 15 Megabytes (Box 4)
  - Observer, 1973-03-23; UP055.004.004.00021; 1 Digital Object(s); 21 Megabytes (Box 4)
  - Observer, 1973-04-01; UP055.004.004.00022; 1 Digital Object(s); 9 Megabytes (Box 4)
  - Observer, 1973-04-13; UP055.004.004.00023; 1 Digital Object(s); 20 Megabytes (Box 4)
    Administration, 1972-73. American Association of University Professors [AAUP] (Tufts) urges Administration to give written reasons in not re-hiring.; Administration, 1972-73. Affirms support for ex-college class, "Zionism reconsidered."
  - Observer, 1973-04-20; UP055.004.004.00024; 1 Digital Object(s); 25 Megabytes (Box 4)
    [Afro-American Society] Members challenge right of University to select director, p. 1; [American association of University professors] Committee established to study future of the University
  - Observer, 1973-04-27; UP055.004.004.00025; 1 Digital Object(s); 20 Megabytes (Box 4)
  - Observer, 1973-05-04; UP055.004.004.00026; 1 Digital Object(s); 20 Megabytes (Box 4)
  - Observer, 1973-05-11; UP055.004.004.00027; 1 Digital Object(s); 15 Megabytes (Box 4)
    [American association of University professors] Report of study by Jack Schnup's Committee favors no quotas
- Tufts Observer, 1973 -- 1974; UP055.005; 1 Volumes; 25 Digital Object(s)
  This series consists of bound volumes of the Tufts Observer newspaper, dated from September 14, 1973 to May 24, 1974. In 1969, the Observer replaced the Tufts Weekly as the weekly student-published paper. Observer states that its objective is to be 'the newspaper of record' for Tufts University. The Observer covers current events and university news and sports. Typical features include editorials and opinion pieces, a calendar of events, art and culture articles, creative works, and comics.
  - Tufts Observer, 1973-09-14; UP055.005.005.00001; 1 Digital Object(s); 14 Megabytes (Box 5)
    Administration 1973. Somerville's Mayor Ralph plans $85,000 tax bill for Tufts.
  - Tufts Observer, 1973-09-21; UP055.005.005.00002; 1 Digital Object(s); 20 Megabytes (Box 5)
    Administration 1973-74. Lonnie Carton. Professor denied tenure, hires lawyer; [Afro-American Society] "Activism and Dedication", keys to Black liberation: Lecture at Cohen (2 Photos), p.1.
  - Tufts Observer, 1973-09-28; UP055.005.005.00003; 1 Digital Object(s); 20 Megabytes (Box 5)
    Alumni/ae increase gifts to development fund; [American association of University professors] Tenure and collective bargaining issues
  - Tufts Observer, 1973-10-05; UP055.005.005.00004; 1 Digital Object(s); 20 Megabytes (Box 5)
    [Afro-American Cultural Center] New director, Allen Colon, outlines plans, p. 2.
  - Tufts Observer, 1973-10-12; UP055.005.005.00005; 1 Digital Object(s); 25 Megabytes (Box 5)
  - Tufts Observer, 1973-10-19; UP055.005.005.00006; 1 Digital Object(s); 20 Megabytes (Box 5)
    [American association of University professors] Conflict of faculty and administration over salaries, imminent issues; Administration 1973-74. University Offers aid to Chelsea disaster fire victims; [Afro-American Society] Solicits help for drought victims in West Africa, p. 2.
  - Tufts Observer, 1973-10-26; UP055.005.005.00007; 1 Digital Object(s); 24 Megabytes (Box 5)
  - Tufts Observer, 1973-11-02; UP055.005.005.00008; 1 Digital Object(s); 19 Megabytes (Box 5)
  - Tufts Observer, 1973-11-09; UP055.005.005.00009; 1 Digital Object(s); 29 Megabytes (Box 5)